A Guide to the George E. Hoffer Automobile Catalogue Collection 1960-present
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
George E. Hoffer Automobile Catalogue 1960-present
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 301
40 linear feet
George E. Hoffer
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions
Acquisition Information
The collection was a gift to Special Collections and Archives from George E. Hoffer, professor of economics in the VCU School of Business.
Biographical/Historical Information
George E. Hoffer is a professor of economics in VCU's School of Business. He has focused his research in the last 30 years on the automobile industry. He came to VCU in 1970. He received a B.S. from the University of Richmond, an M.S. from Virginia Polytechnic Insititue and State University and a Ph.D. from the University of Virginia. He came to VCU in 1970. Hoffer has authored or co-authored approximately 60 academic articles on the economics of the auto industry. He has also conducted research for the Federal Trade Commission, the Attorney General's Office of Virginia, and for the Virginia Department of Motor Vehicles.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains domestic and foreign automobile catalogs from most of the major automobile manufacturing companies from the years 1960 through today. The collection also contains: issues of Consumer Reports magazine focusing on automobiles from 1987 through 2002; car buying guides, 1974-2002; gas mileage guides, 1997 - 2002; correspondence, mainly from car manufacturers; and newspaper clippings.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically by subject and chronological therein.
Organization
Series I is made up of domestic (American) automobile catalogs, Series II contains foreign automobile catalogs -- all of which are arranged chronologically. Series III is composed of issues of Consumer Reports, correspondence and miscellaneous material, including newspaper clippings.
Contents List
- Series I-Domestic
  - Buick 1960-1963 (Box 1)
  - Buick 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Cadillac 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Chevrolet 1960-1963 (Box 1)
  - Chevrolet 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Chrysler 1960-1966 (Box 1)
  - Ford 1960-1966 (Box 1)
  - Oldsmobile 1960-1963 (Box 1)
  - Oldsmobile 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Pontiac 1960-1962 (Box 1)
  - Pontiac 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Rambler 1960-1966 (Box 1)
  - Studebaker 1960-1966 (Box 1)
  - Buick 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - Cadillac 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - Chevrolet 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - Chrysler 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - Ford 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - Pontiac 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - Rambler 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - American Motors Company/AMC 1970-1974 (Box 3)
  - Buick 1970-1974 (Box 3)
  - Chevrolet 1970-1974 (Box 3)
  - Chrysler 1970-1974 (Box 3)
  - Ford (1 of 2) 1970-1974 (Box 3a)
  - Ford (2 of 2) 1970-1974 (Box 3a)
  - Pontiac 1970-1974 (Box 3a)
  - American Motors Company 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Buick 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Cadillac 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Chevrolet 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Chrysler 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Ford (1 of 2) 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Ford (2 of 2) 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Oldsmobile 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Pontiac 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - American Motors Company 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Buick 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Cadillac 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Chevrolet (1 of 2) 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Chevrolet (2 of 2) 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Chrysler (1 of 2) 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Chrysler (2 of 2) 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Ford (1 of 3) 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Ford (2 of 3) 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Ford (3 of 3) 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Oldsmobile 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Pontiac 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - American Motors Company 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Cadillac 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Chevrolet 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Chrysler 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Ford (1 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Ford (2 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Oldsmobile 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Pontiac 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - American Motors Company 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Buick 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Chevrolet 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Chrysler (1 of 2) 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Chrysler (2 of 2) 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Ford (1 of 3) 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Ford (2 of 3) 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Ford (3 of 3) 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Oldsmobile 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - Pontiac 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - American Motors Company (1 of 2) 1985-1987 (Box 8)
  - American Motors Company (2 of 2) 1985-1987 (Box 8)
  - Buick (1 of 3) 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Buick (2 of 3) 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Buick (3 of 3) 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Cadillac 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Chevrolet 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Chrysler (1 of 5) 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Chrysler (2 of 5) 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Chrysler (3 of 5) 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Chrysler (4 of 5) 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Chrysler (5 of 5) 1985-1987 (Box 9)
  - Ford (1 of 5) 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - Ford (2 of 5) 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - Ford (3 of 5) 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - Ford (4 of 5) 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - Ford (5 of 5) 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - Oldsmobile (1 of 2) 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - Oldsmobile (2 of 2) 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - Pontiac 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - American Motors Company (1 of 2) 1988-1990 (Box 11)
  - American Motors Company (2 of 2) 1988-1990 (Box 11)
  - Cadillac 1988-1990 (Box 11)
  - Chevrolet (1 of 2) 1988-1990 (Box 11)
  - Chevrolet (2 of 2) 1988-1990 (Box 11)
  - Chrysler ( 1 of 3) 1988-1990 (Box 11)
  - Chrysler (2 of 3) 1988-1990 (Box 12)
  - Chrysler (3 of 3) 1988-1990 (Box 12)
  - Ford (1 of 4) 1988-1990 (Box 12)
  - Ford (2 of 4) 1988-1990 (Box 12)
  - Ford (3 of 4) 1988-1990 (Box 12)
  - Ford (4 of 4) 1988-1990 (Box 13)
  - Oldsmobile 1988-1990 (Box 13)
  - Pontiac 1988-1990 (Box 13)
  - American Motors (1 of 2) 1991-1993 (Box 13)
  - American Motors Company (2 of 2) 1991-1993 (Box 13)
  - Buick (1 of 2) 1991-1993 (Box 14)
  - Buick (2 of 2) 1991-1993 (Box 14)
  - Cadillac 1991-1993 (Box 14)
  - Chevrolet (1 of 3) 1991-1993 (Box 14)
  - Chevrolet (2 of 3) 1991-1993 (Box 14)
  - Chevrolet (3 of 3) 1991-1993 (Box 14)
  - Chrysler (1 of 3) 1991-1993 (Box 14)
  - Chrysler (2of 3) 1991-1993 (Box 15)
  - Chrysler (3 of 3) 1991-1993 (Box 15)
  - Ford (1 of 4) 1991-1993 (Box 15)
  - Ford (2 of 4) 1991-1993 (Box 15)
  - Ford (3 of 4) 1991-1993 (Box 15)
  - Ford (4 of 4) 1991-1993 (Box 15)
  - Oldsmobile 1991-1993 (Box 15)
  - Pontiac 1991-1993 (Box 16)
  - Saturn 1991-1993 (Box 16)
  - American Motors Company 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Buick 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Cadillac 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Chevrolet (1 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Chevrolet (2 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Buick 1996 (Box 17)
  - Chrysler (1 of 2) 1994-1996 (Box 17)
  - Chrysler (2 of 2) 1994-1996 (Box 17)
  - Ford (1 of 2) 1994-1996 (Box 17)
  - Ford (2 of 2) 1994-1996 (Box 17)
  - General Motors 1995-1996 (Box 17)
  - Oldsmobile (1 of 2) 1994-1996 (Box 17)
  - Oldsmobile (2 of 2) 1994-1996 (Box 17)
  - Pontiac 1994-1996 (Box 17)
  - Saturn 1994-1996 (Box 17)
  - Buick 1997 (Box 18)
  - Cadillac 1996-1997 (Box 18)
  - Chevrolet 1996-1997 (Box 18)
  - Chrysler 1997 (Box 18)
  - Dodge 1996-1997 (Box 18)
  - Eagle 1997 (Box 18)
  - Ford 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  - Geo 1997 (Box 18)
  - General Motors 1997 (Box 18)
  - Hummer 1996 (Box 18)
  - Lincoln/Mercury 1996 (Box 18)
  - Oldsmobile 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  - Plymouth 1996-1997 (Box 18)
  - Pontiac 1996-1997 (Box 18)
  - Saturn 1997 (Box 18)
  - Buick 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Cadillac 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Chevrolet/Chevy 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Chrysler 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Dodge 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Ford 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - General Motors (EV1) 1997 (Box 19)
  - Geo 1997 (Box 19)
  - GMC 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Hummer 1997 (Box 19)
  - Infiniti 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Jeep 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Land Rover 1997 (Box 19)
  - Lexus 1998 (Box 19)
  - Lincoln 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Nissan 1998 (Box 19)
  - Oldsmobile 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Plymouth 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Pontiac 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Saturn 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Buick 1999 (Box 20)
  - Caddy 1999 (Box 20)
  - Chevrolet 1999 (Box 20)
  - Chrysler 1999 (Box 20)
  - Dodge/Ram 1999 (Box 20)
  - Ford 1999 (Box 20)
  - GMC 1999 (Box 20)
  - Kia 1999 (Box 20)
  - Pontiac 1999 (Box 20)
  - Subaru 1999 (Box 20)
  - Buick 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Cadillac 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Chevrolet 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Chrysler 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Corvette 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Dodge 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Federal Coach 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Ford 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - General Motors 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - GMC 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Hummer 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Jeep 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Land Rover 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Lincoln 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Mercury 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Monte Carlo 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Oldsmobile 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Plymouth 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Pontiac 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Richmond Times Dispatch 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Virginia International Auto Show 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Western Star Trucks 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Buick 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Cadillac 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Chevrolet 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Ford 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Hummer 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Jeep 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Lincoln 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Oldsmobile 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Pontiac 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Mercury 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Saturn 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Buick 2002 (Box 23)
  - Cadillac 2002 (Box 23)
  - Chevrolet 2002 (Box 23)
  - Jeep 2002 (Box 23)
  - Pontiac 2002 (Box 23)
- Series II-Foreign
  - Alfa Romeo 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Audi 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - BMW 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Fiat 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Honda 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Isuzu 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Jaguar 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Mazda 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Mercedes-Benz (1 of 2) 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Mercedes-Benz (2 of 2) 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Midget 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Nissan/Datsun 1960-1982 (Box 1)
  - Peugot 1960-1982 (Box 2)
  - Saab 1960-1982 (Box 2)
  - Subaru 1960-1982 (Box 2)
  - Toyota 1960-1982 (Box 2)
  - Triumph 1960-1982 (Box 2)
  - Volkswagen 1960-1982 (Box 2)
  - Volvo 1960-1982 (Box 2)
  - Alfa-Romeo 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Audi 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - BMW 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Fiat 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Honda 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Isuzu 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Mercedes-Benz 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Nissan 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Peugot 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Saab 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Subaru 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Toyota 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Volkswagen 1983-1986 (Box 3)
  - Volvo 1983-1986 (Box 4)
  - Alfa Romeo 1986-1990 (Box 4)
  - Audi 1986-1990 (Box 4)
  - BMW 1986-1990 (Box 4)
  - Honda 1986-1990 (Box 4)
  - Hyundai 1986-1990 (Box 4)
  - Isuzu 1986-1990 (Box 4)
  - Mazada 1986-1990 (Box 4)
  - Mercedes-Benz (1 of 2) 1986-1990 (Box 5)
  - Mercedes-Benz (2 of 2) 1986-1990 (Box 5)
  - Mitsubishi 1986-1990 (Box 5)
  - Nissan 1986-1990, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Peugot 1986-1990 (Box 5)
  - Porsche 1986-1990 (Box 5)
  - Saab 1986-1990 (Box 5)
  - Subaru 1986-1990 (Box 5)
  - Suzuki 1986-1990 (Box 5)
  - Toyota 1986-1990, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Volkswagen 1986-1990 (Box 6)
  - Volvo 1986-1990 (Box 6)
  - Audi 1991-1992 (Box 6)
  - BMW 1991-1992 (Box 6)
  - Honda 1991-1992, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Hyundai 1991-1992 (Box 6)
  - Isuzu 1991-1992 (Box 6)
  - Jaguar 1991-1992 (Box 6)
  - Mazada 1991-1992, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Mercedes-Benz 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Mitsubishi 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Nissan 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Porsche 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Subaru 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Suzuki 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Toyota 1991-1992, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Volkswagen 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Volvo 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Audi 1993-1995 (Box 8)
  - BMW 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Honda 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Hyundai 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Isuzu 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Land Rover 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Mazada 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Mercedes-Benz 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Mitsubishi 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Nissan 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Porsche 1993-1995 (Box 8)
  - Saab 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Subaru 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Suzuki 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Toyota 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Volkswagen 1993-1995 (Box 8)
  - Volvo 1993-1995 (Box 8)
  - Audi 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - BMW 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Honda 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Hyundai (3-D Magic Eye poster) 1997 (Box 9)
  - Isuzu 1996 (Box 9)
  - Kia 1996 (Box 9)
  - Land Rover 1997 (Box 9)
  - Mazda 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Mercedes 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Mitsubishi 1997 (Box 9)
  - Nissan 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Porsche 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Saab 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Subaru 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Suzuki 1996 (Box 9)
  - Toyota 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Volkswagen 1997 (Box 9)
  - Volvo 1996 (Box 9)
  - Acura 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Audi 1997-1999 (Box 10)
  - BMW 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Honda 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Hyundai 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Isuzu 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Jaguar 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Mazda 1997-1999 (Box 10)
  - Mercedes-Benz 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Mitsubishi 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Nissan 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Porsche 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Saab 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Subaru 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Suzuki 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Toyota 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Volkswagen 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Volvo 1997-1999 (Box 10)
  - BMW 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Daewoo 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Honda 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Hyundai 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Infiniti 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Isuzu 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Jaguar 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - KIA 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Lexus 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Lincoln Town Car 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Mazda 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Mercedes Benz 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Mitsubishi 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Nissan 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Porsche 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Saab 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Saturn 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Smart 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Subaru 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Suzuki 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Toyota 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Volkswagen 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Volvo 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Acura 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Audi 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - BMW 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Daewoo 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Honda 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Hyundai 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Isuzu 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Jaguar 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - KIA 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Land Rover 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Mazda 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Mercedes Benz 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Mitsubishi 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Nissan 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Porsche 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Saab 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Suzuki 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Toyota 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Volvo 2000-2001 (Box 12)
  - Mercedes 2002 (Box 13)
  - Saab 2002 (Box 13)
  - Subaru 2002 (Box 13)
  - Toyota 2002 (Box 13)
- Series III-Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Car Buying Made Easier Guides 1974-1988 (Box 1)
  - Gas Mileage Guides 1975- (Box 1)
  - Consumer Report Magazines 1987- (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d., 9 folders (Box 2)